Guide to the George Cornell Supplee papers, 1902-1948.
Supplee, George Cornell papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
George Cornell Supplee papers, 1902-1948.
6976
George Cornell Supplee 1889-1949.
.5 cubic feet.
Printed material, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection includes publications authored or co-authored by Supplee and some other of his papers.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
George Cornell Supplee BS '13, MS '14, PhD '19 was a biochemist who worked in the milk industry. He was employed by the Casein Co. of America and the Dry Milk Co. where he managed a laboratory. The company was later absorbed into the Bordon Co. He later founded his own consulting group called the G. C. Supplee Research Corp. Several documents from his highschool give his name as George Charles Supplee.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection includes a disbound volume containing publications authored or co-authored by Supplee, mostly pertaining to milk and nutrition. A chemistry book from his coursework at Cornell annoted by him throughout. Also his Cornell Ph.D diploma and various certificates.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Supplee, George Cornell,1889-1949.; Supplee, George Cornell, 1889-1949.
Subjects:
Dairy bacteriology.; Milk--Analysis.; Milk--Microbiology.; Vitamins.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Formerly bound volume of Supplee's publications
  Various publications and reprints of which Supplee was an author. Many of the publications have additional authors as well.
  - Variations in the Tests for Fat in Cream and Skimmed Milk, April 1915 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Preliminary Note on Certain Changes in Some of the Nitrogenous Constituents of Milk Caused by Bacteria, November 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Lecithin Content of Butter and its Possible Relationship to the Fishy Flavor, November 1919 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Relation of Fodder to the Antiscorbutic Potency and Salt Content of Milk, December 1920 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Comparaison au point de vue nutritif des laits liquides et desseches; Variations in Bacteria Counts from Milk as Affected by Media and Incubation Temperature; Bacterial Quality of Machine and Hand Drawn Milk; Citric Acid Content of Milk and Milk Products, July-October 1921 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fat Analysis of Milk Powder; Bacterial Content of Milk Powder; The Copper Content of Cows' Milk; Bacteria Counts of Milk Powder as Obtained by the Microscopic Method; Bacterial Counts of Milk as Obtained by Various Media; Constructive Policies and Methods for Milk Improvement, January-November 1922 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Copper as a Constituent in Woman's and Cow's Milk. Its Absorption and Excretion by the Infant; Report of Committee on Dairy Methods, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Report of Committee on Dairy Methods; The Keeping Quality of Dry Milk; Sur la solubilite de la poudre de lait, November 1924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Solubility of Milk Powder as Affected by Moisture Content; Dry Milk for School Service, January-April 1925 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Humidity Equilibria of Milk Powders; Variations in the Antiscorbutic Properties of Dry Milk; Method of Packing Food Products Container Therefor, January-May 1926 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Richesse en vitamines du lait liquide et du lait sec; The Use of Milk in Bread; Antirachitic Properties of Irradiated Dry Milk, January-September 1917 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Concentrated Water Soluble Fraction of Milk as a Source of Vitamin B, September 1928 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Bacteriology of Dry Milk, May 1929 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Seasonal Variations in Certain Inorganic Constituents of Dry Milk Produced in New York and Wisconsin; The Action of Irradiated Ergosterol on Rats and Chickens, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Comparative Antirachitic and Calcifying Properties of Irradiated Milk and Milk Derivatives; The Effect of Ultraviolet Irradiation on the Antiscorbutic Vitamin of Liquid and Dry Milk; Method of Irradiating Milk Solids with Ultra-Violet Rays and the Product of Such Method; The Relative Antineuritic (Vitamin "B") Potency of Certain Milk Derivatives; The Growth-Promoting Properties (Vitamin B Complex) of the Concentrated Water-Soluble Portion of Milk, May-October 1931 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Le lait naturel liquide et le lait sec dans l'etiologie de certaines anemies; Irradiated Milk: The Energy Requirements for Antirachitic Activation; Irradiated Milk: The Amount of Vitamin D and its Rate of Formation; L'activation antirachitique du lait au point de vue physique et biologique; Irradiated Milk: The Amount of Energy Required to Prevent Rickets in Chickens; The Vitamin "B" and "G" Content of Dry Skimmed Milk and Dry Whey; Irradiated Milk: The Influence of the Intensity and Character of the Radiations on the Antirachitic Potency; The Prevention and Cure of Rickets through Irradiated Milk, January-November 1932 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Antirachitic Activation of Milk by Direct Irradiation with Ultra-Violet Rays; Vitamin A Content of Milk Irradiated by Various Carbon Arcs; The Irradiation of Milk with Ultra Violet Rays; Vitamin D Milk, March-October 1933 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Studies on the Iodine Content of Milk; Process of Producing Beta Lactose; The Cholesterol Content and the Antirachitic Activation of Milk Constituents; Irradiated Milk: The Transmission and Antirachitic Activation of Milk Films by Ultra-Violet Radiations; Irradiated Milk: The Influence of Fat Content and Time of Exposure on the Antirachitic Potency; Irradiated Milk: Characteristics of the Flowing Film Required for Optimum Efficiency of Antirachitic Activation; Irradiated Milk: The Reflecting Properties and Antirachitic Activation as Affected by the Impingment Angle of the Incident Radiation; A Vitamin B Deficient Ration; The Vitamin B Supplementation of Milk; Certain Foam Producing Substances of Milk; The Iodine Content of Milk as Affected by Feeding Iodized Dry Milk; Casein Vitamin-Free, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Process of Making Vitamin-Containing Material; Photochemical Phenomena Involved in Vitamin G (B2) Studies; The Value of the Recording Ultraviolet Meter in the Irradiation of Milk; Precipitation of Proteinaceous Matter by Chlorine, July-November 1935 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Irradiated Evaporated Milk: The Transmission and Antirachitic Activation of Evaporated Milk Films by Ultra-Violet Radiations; The Fluorometric Estimation of Lactoflavin; Lactoflavin {and C17H20N4O6}; Lactoflavin, A Possible Contaminant of Vitamin-Free Diets; Lactoflavin, A Necessary Growth-Promoting Dietary Factor; The Influence of Dextrin and Sucrose on Growth and Dermatitis; Labco Products for Biological Research {and Supplement A1}; The Influence of Milk Constituents on the Effectiveness of Vitamin D; Pellagra-like Syndrome in Chicks; Lactoflavin in Nutrition, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Significance of Quantitative Relationships in Vitamin B Complex Studies, N1937 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Method of Irradiation; A Standard Method for the Determination of Vitamin B1, January-November 1938 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Fluid Irradiator; Canine Pediatrics: a collection of discussions from Veterinary Medicine on Nutrition in Young Puppies; Determining Riboflavin; a Fluorometric and Biologial Method; American Pharmaceutical Manufacturers' Association Mid=year Meeting Address, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Concentration and Isolation of Water-Soluble Vitamins; Treatment of Whey; Whey as a Source of Vitamins and Vitamin Products; Method of Producing Vitamin D Product; Apparatus for Irradiation; Method of Irradiating Liquids; Method of and Apparatus for Irradiating Liquids; The Effect of Complementing Factors on the Quantitative Response and Specificity of Vitamin B6; Equilibrium Solutions of Certain Lactose-Salt Mixtures; Riboflavin is a Catalyst Controlling the Efficiency of Cellular Oxidation; The Instantaneous Heat Treatment of Milk, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Preparation of Vitamin B Concentrate; The Instantaneous Heat Treatment of Milk; Labco Products for Biological Research; Method for Purifying Lactoflavin; The Chemical Determination of Nicotinic Acid in Milk and Milk Derivatives; Factors Affecting the Gas Content of Milk; The Lethal Effectiveness of Ultra Violet Rays Applied to Milk, November 1941 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Interrelated Vitamin Requirements: Kidney Damage, Adrenal Hemorrhage and Cardiac Failure Correlated with Inadequacy of Pantothenic Acid; Factors Affecting the Riboflavin Content of the Liver; The Inverse Ratio between Flouride in Food and Drink and Dental Caries; Interrelated Vitamin Requirements, March-July 1942 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Cardiotoxic Adreno-Sympathetic Activity in Vitamin B Deficiencies, May 1944 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - The Varying Requirement for Choline for Normal Metabolism of Proteins (Casein, Lactalbumin, and Soy Protein) with Particular Reference to the Hepatico-Renal Syndrome; A Comparison of Choline, Betaine and Dimethyl-Aminoethanol in the Prevention of the Hepatico-Renal Syndrome; Liquid Treating Method, June-August 1945 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Differential Nitrogen Retention from Caseion, Lactalbumin, and Soy Protein, and Hydrolysates Therefrom, October 1946 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Chemical Research and the Milk Industry, January 1948 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Miscellaneous notes, obituary, photo, New York Academy of Sciences and American Public Health Association certificates and First Year Academic certificate from Penn Yan Academy.. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Supplee's copy of The Vitamin B Requirement of Man by George R. Cowgill, published by Yale University Press., 1934 (Box 1)
  Stamped as from the The Dry Milk Company, Inc. Research Laboratories, Bainbridge, N.Y.
- Supplee's copy of the Laboratory Manual to Accompany Clarke and Dennis's Elementary Chemistry by L. M. Dennis and F. W. Clarke., 1902 (Box 1)
  Signed by Supplee with his 210 College Ave address from while at Cornell. The book is extensively annotated by Supplee.
- Penn Yan Academy diploma, 1909 (Folder 1)
- University of the State of New York regents diploma, 1900 (Folder 1)
- Cornell University Bachelor of Science diploma, 1913 (Folder 1)
- Cornell Doctor of Philosophy diploma, 1919 (Folder 1)
- The Society of the Sigma Xi, 1920 (Folder 1)
- American Medical Association Silver Medal at the Scientific Exhibit of the Kansas City Session, 1936 (Folder 1)
- American Institute of Chemists Fellow certificates, 1938 (Folder 1)